Tressa Bidelman

2810 Oakmont Drive

Montgomery, IL 60538 • 630-340-8730

tressabidelman@gmail.com



Objective

A graduate of the University of Illinois – Chicago in Anthropology and currently pursuing a Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction at DePaul University. My purpose is to use my knowledge in cultural variation and human behavior along with my extensive customer service experience to understand your specific users and provide your organization with the most dynamic user experience for your platform.

Skills

UX Methods

Card sorting Ethnography Low/Mid/High-fidelity Interviewing Personas Paper Prototyping Site-mapping Sketching **Usability Testing** Wireframing

Web Development

HTML CSS

Technical Skills

Balsamiq Axure Photoshop

Experience

All Campus Senior Enrollment Advisor

August 2013 – Present

- Manage portfolio of graduate level programs and provided additional support for all other programs in the organization.
- Work closely with and present to; marketing, account management, web design and analytics in order to improve processes and lead generation opportunities.
- Troubleshoot software including and various landing pages to provide performance feedback.
- Professionally assisted prospective students through the admissions process in accordance with all applicable federal and state regulations, school policies, procedures, and in compliance with all accrediting standards and requirements.
- Knowledge about higher education and graduate degree programs to ensure that all prospective students receive the story about the college and future career opportunities.
- Present at on-site open houses, networking events, conferences, as well as to clients on their campus to create new client relationships and foster current relationships.
- Present online orientation to all accepted students remotely.

DeVry University Senior Advisor

February 2011 – August 2013

- Identified prospective student needs and concerns to match them with the best program.
- Proactively worked with other departments to ensure student satisfaction.

- Networked and developed professional relationships to generate personally-developed inquiries.
- Conducted personal interviews to determine student interest and eligibility with DeVry University.
- Presented and organized New Student Orientation each session which includes presenting the online format to prepare new students for success.

Wheels Inc. - Des Plaines, IL Fleet Consulting Manager

May 2007 - October 2008

- Responsible for maintaining relationships with clients as well as internal employees, resolving service issues, client retention, selling operating services and growing clients' full potential.
- Presented quarterly reviews to customers including cost benefit analysis and recommendations based on the clients needs.
- Successfully instituted new accounts by working with various departments such as accounting, human resources, purchasing or whomever the client saw fit to be involved.
- Achieved an average of three client visits per day while managing email and phone communications to meet client needs and to strengthen client relationships.
- Tracked and researched market trends, service performance and client satisfaction on a monthly basis.
- Delivered unprecedented consultation by accompanying clients on their vendor visits as well as acting on the client's behalf to achieve the best product and service that meets their specific needs.
- Attended conferences to maintain top knowledge of the products and people in the industry.

Senior Account Executive

August 2005 - May 2007

- In addition to Account Executive role, responsible for the development and execution of a new product for executive clients.
- Responsibilities included research and correspondence with all operating departments, creation and implementation of procedures for operating departments and presentation of the product including a budget proposal.

Account Executive

August 2002 - August 2005

- Anticipated client need and developed tactical plans to address and meet those needs.
- Matched profitable services with client expectations.
- Utilized market knowledge and trends to counsel clients on various options to help establish a successful and unique program.
- Used selling techniques to help steer clients toward mutually beneficial solutions to their issues.
- Educated and gained support from internal partners as to the unique requirements of the client.
- Successfully procured the business of reputable clients based on my premier customer service.

Education

DePaul University
MS of Human-Computer Interaction

September 2014 - present

University of Illinois-Chicago BA – Anthropology

May 2000